[theme music playing]
-[Julio] You're not using your brain!
-Ouch!
You imbecile! Show some dignity!
I don't care about what people say.
[shouting] You are right!
I am the governor,
and I can do anything I want!
[Arnaldo chuckles] A lunatic escaped me.
-That lunatic got away!
-[gunshots]
If the congressman asks
if I've already dealt with Arthur,
-do you know what to say?
-You don't have to tell me.
[Ivy] Tomorrow, the Ardientes will wake up
to a living nightmare.
-This is the Senator's cut.
-Is this all of it?
That's the Senator's. Give it to him.
[Ivy] If the issue spreads,
the media will swarm you,
especially because you passed
the Anti-Gambling Bill.
[reporter] But how
do you explain your name
being mentioned in the video itself?
Our empire is falling,
and I need to save it.
Just prove to everyone
that we Ardientes are good people,
that we are innocent.
But you are innocent, right?
Everything they're accusing us of is true.
[Ivy] The Ardiente's downfall
is within reach.
I will fix this. We will fix this.
I'll talk to my parents
and track down whoever
is messing with the Ardientes.
When I'm gone, all this will be yours.
You will be the king
of Poblacion Ardiente.
[Diego] Don't you think
it's time for our family to change?
We don't have to change anything.
In Ardiente, we are the rulers!
Raul, you moron!
This is all your fault!
-[Raul] I'll kill you!
-Stop it! Stop!
[Emilia] Papa! Papa!
Papa! [crying]
What are you looking at? Get help!
Call an ambulance! Hurry!
-Call an ambulance! Help!
-Help!
-[Arnaldo] Grandpa!
-[Emilia] Papa!
Call an ambulance! Call an ambulance!
[Raul] Diego, call an ambulance. Hurry!
Papa!
[Emilia sobbing]
-Hello?
-Papa!
This is Mayor Arnaldo.
Mayor of Poblacion Ardiente.
I need an ambulance here in our mansion.
Pronto!
-[Emilia] Papa!
-What happened?
Papa!
[sobbing] Papa.
[Emilia wailing]
-[shushes]
-[Tonio] Hey!
Lily… Run!
Mom.
Mom?
[sobbing]
Mom.
Mom! Mom!
[pensive music playing]
-[Emilia] Papa!
-[Arnaldo] Hurry! Double time!
Papa, don't leave us!
Arnaldo, make sure
your grandfather survives!
I will. I'll go with them.
Let's go, let's go!
[sobs]
[siren wailing]
Mom, what happened to grandpa?
[tense music playing]
He and your dad had a fight.
Then he had a heart attack.
Go follow your brother. He needs you.
Okay, Mom, Dad.
[ominous music plays]
Ouch! Ouch! Hey! It hurts! Watch it.
Relax. It's me. Ouch!
What's wrong with you?
Jepoy, you're lucky I don't have a gun,
or I could've shot you on the spot.
-I'm sorry.
-Why are you here?
Julio Ardiente's in the hospital.
He had a heart attack.
[tense music playing]
[doctor] I'm sorry, Mayor.
This is as far as you can go.
-Mayor.
-Doc.
I'll leave him in your hands.
Don't worry.
We will do everything for him.
Thank you.
You tried to kill him, Raul!
You monster! You tried to kill him!
Please listen to me.
I didn't mean to, Emilia.
-I wasn't thinking straight. I just--
-Get out. Get out!
I was just hurt by what he said to me.
-I lost it--
-Leave me alone!
I'd never do that to your father.
-Hear me out first.
-Leave me alone!
Get out.
Get out!
[ominous music playing]
Arnaldo. How's grandpa doing?
He's in the OR now.
He's in critical condition.
He needs surgery.
Cardiac arrest.
But it doesn't make sense.
Why did the doctor say
there could be asphyxiation involved?
What happened back there?
Mom said grandpa had a heart attack
because he and dad fought.
Yes, we heard them.
But why did the doctor say
asphyxiation was involved?
[sobbing]
[dramatic music playing]
Papa.
[Julio] This is all your fault.
You.
You and your weaknesses as a woman.
Straighten yourself out! Understand?
[sobs]
If he dies…
What will happen if Papa dies?
[Ivy] You're only a governor in name.
I can see how you let your father
boss you around.
Maybe it's time you show them
that you can stand beside them.
Not as a woman, but as an Ardiente.
[dramatic music playing]
[Julio] Did you forget
that you're the governor?
Getting drunk like that?
You have no self-respect!
I don't care about what people say!
You are right!
I am the governor,
and I can do anything I want!
Stop treating me like your puppet!
Starting now, I am in charge of my life!
[ominous music playing]
[thinking] If Papa dies,
I can take his place.
[chuckling]
How is your grandfather?
He's in the operating room, critical.
Mom, where's Dad?
He's blaming himself for what happened.
They were arguing when
your grandfather had a heart attack.
Was that all that happened, Mom?
I was there.
Are you doubting me?
Well, doctors found something different.
Grandpa was strangled.
What? That's outrageous.
Your dad would never do that
to your grandfather.
Okay. Let's just wait
for the doctor's findings.
And the people should know
about what happened.
I have to call someone.
[line ringing]
Hello?
The congressman is sick.
Cancel all his meetings.
And call some reporters
to come to the hospital.
So, what's your plan?
[phone ringing]
-Yes, Emilia?
-Did I wake you up?
No, it's okay. Why?
Papa had a heart attack.
What?
Uh… How is he?
He's very critical.
Um… Emilia, just relax.
I'll go see you.
Thank you, Ivy. You're a real friend.
Thank you.
It looks like Congressman
is in critical condition.
He was rushed to the hospital.
[tense music playing]
They can't keep his real condition
a secret any longer.
Do you really have to go there?
Jepoy, Emilia thinks
we're friends, remember?
That's why I need to make
her feel she can count on me
whenever she's in need.
Besides, I want to see Julio suffering.
Ivy, would you consider this a victory?
Well, this isn't part of my plans.
But I'd like to believe…
that this is a fitting punishment
for all the Ardientes' past sins.
Let's just call this… karma.
[Diego scoffs]
News really does travel fast.
Um… Mr. Torillo, I'm sorry
about what happened to your grandfather.
Sorry?
Why are you apologizing?
Is it your fault he had a heart attack?
[tense music playing]
Fine.
Mr. Torillo, if you don't want me
to sympathize with your family,
I won't force it.
Excuse me.
You know… I just realized.
Whenever something bad happens
to my family, you're always there.
Why is that?
Can you explain, Ms. Aguas?
Why are you so concerned about my family?
Diego?
What are you doing?
Uh, Mom, I was just asking
Ms. Aguas something.
Ivy, thank you for coming.
Of course, Emilia. How is the congressman?
He's still in the OR.
I hope the operation goes well.
And I'm hoping for the same.
Let's go to the OR.
I want to be the first
to see him when he wakes up.
-Sure.
-Come.
All right.
[scoffs]
[unsettling music playing]
I'm afraid the condition
of the patient is not stable.
He needs to be transferred
to a better-equipped hospital.
He needs to undergo a triple bypass
operation as soon as possible.
But he's going to be okay, doc, right?
[doctor] Well, I'm not so sure.
But I know he needs
special medical attention.
And he needs it now.
Do everything you can, doc, to make
his transfer to Manila comfortable.
Get the elite heart surgeons.
I want him to undergo surgery
as soon as possible.
Doc, you mentioned something
about asphyxiation.
Was that the cause of his heart attack?
[unsettling music playing]
Uh… Well, I'm sorry,
but there was some confusion.
That was actually another patient.
The heart attack of the congressman
is due to stress.
-Thank you so much, doc.
-Okay, I have to go now.
I have to attend to my other patients.
[sighs]
-[man] Gov, how is the congressman?
-[nurse] Hold on. You can't go there.
Hold on. Why are those people here?
Diego, Arnaldo.
Stop. We have to accommodate them.
Now is the best time
to get the sympathy of the public.
Now, you two, be nice.
Come. We're ready. Stay here, Diego.
[reporter] What happened
to the congressman?
[speaker id] He had a heart attack.
He is in a very critical condition now.
He's going to be transferred
to Manila for his surgery.
[reporter] What caused the heart attack?
[ominous music playing]
[tense music playing]
Should I put an end
to your suffering, Julio?
Just say the word…
And I'll remove the tubes
keeping you alive, one by one.
[tense music swelling]
What caused the heart attack?
Everyone knows our family is
going through a lot of stress.
You know the congressman.
Even when his reputation
was being questioned,
he kept on working to make sure
that Poblacion Ardiente is safe.
[nurse] Hi, ma'am. Excuse me.
You have to leave the room
so we can prepare
the congressman for transport.
[tense music playing]
Ma'am, who do you think
is attacking your family?
-We're still investigating.
-[clears throat]
[Arnaldo] But I want to assure
the people of Poblacion Ardiente
that, while the congressman is resting,
his undying service
to this town will continue.
I will personally
take care of his affairs.
[clears throat]
Honestly, now is not the best
time to talk about politics.
What's important is the
congressman's speedy recovery, right?
So, to our supporters
in Poblacion Ardiente,
we need your prayers
for the speedy recovery
of our beloved congressman.
Governor, one more question!
Um, enough, enough.
That is all. Thank you.
Diego, Arnaldo.
-Gov.
-Ivy.
Emilia.
I'll go ahead to give
your family some privacy.
Thank you for your time.
Of course.
Ivy, thank you
for your concern. I appreciate it.
It's nothing, Mr. Mayor.
I'm on my way out too.
Would you like to ride with me?
No, it's okay, Emilia.
I brought my car with me.
Arnaldo, coordinate with the doctor, okay?
I still have a lot to take care of.
Ivy, I'll take you home.
Arnaldo, you'll be coordinating
with the doctor, remember?
Diego, you see Ivy home.
Why me?
Diego, I said bring Ivy home.
Make sure nothing bad happens to her,
or else you'll answer to me.
Ivy, I'll go ahead.
Arnaldo, take care of your grandfather.
Diego, bring Ivy home.
[tense music playing]
Keep her safe.
Our enemies know she's on our side.
I don't want her to get involved.
Ivy.
[tense music playing]
Let's go.
Maybe now you have an answer
to my question earlier.
What question?
What do you want from my family?
I know what you're doing.
You're toying with my mom and brother.
Mr. Torillo, I can see
that you don't like me.
But I hope despite that,
you won't judge me.
Because you don't know who I am
and what I'm going through.
[quiet music playing]
Well, maybe that's the problem.
I don't know you.
Who are you, Ms. Aguas?
What do you want from my family?
What do you want from this town?
Ever since you arrived,
bad things started happening.
So? Answer my question.
Who are you, Ms. Aguas?
You know what? Just stop the car.
Stop the car.
Stop it.
Get down.
I can go home on my own.
Even if you won't answer my question,
I'll find out
who you really are, Ms. Aguas.
[car accelerating]
[reporter] Why did he have a heart attack?
Everyone knows our family is
going through a lot of stress.
You know the congressman.
Even when his reputation
was being questioned,
he kept on working.
[ominous music playing]
[door opens]
Emilia, why did you do it?
Why did you cover up for me?
Do you want your sons to know
what you did to their grandfather?
I will keep everything a secret
if you do what I want.
You know, Emilia, if you think
you can keep me on a leash,
then you're wrong.
I won't let you do that.
On the contrary, I don't want you here.
If you want, you can stay with
your relatives, if you still have any.
Honestly, you'll only get
in the way of my plans.
What's your plan?
What are you really up to?
You don't have to know
because you're not part of it.
Come, we have a meeting with the family.
[sighs]
Good, you're both here.
Diego, how was your ride with Ivy?
[tense music playing]
I know you're worried
about your grandfather.
But this is not the right time
to be emotional.
We need to hold the fort
while your grandpa is sick.
Arnaldo, you will go with him to Manila.
Ma, I'm the mayor here.
I can't just leave.
I've been a mayor before. I'll handle it.
I can't leave this place because
your grandpa's responsibilities
as a congressman fall on me.
And you're the only one I can trust
to take care of your grandfather.
He's more important to you
than being a mayor, right?
Son, we have to be united in our decision.
We need to show the people
that we're strong.
So, when your grandfather gets better,
he will come back to a strong
and orderly Ardiente.
I am now the matriarch of this family.
[ominous music playing]
Son, I need your support.
All your support.
Raul, sit beside me.
Bring the food!
[ominous music playing]
[Emilia] My time has come.
Now that the king is gone…
I shall reign as queen.
Arnaldo, is the ambulance
that's going to take
your grandfather to Manila ready?
-I've taken care of it.
-Good.
Diego, do you have
your grandfather's things?
-Yes, Mom. Everything's in here.
-Okay.
Governor,
the congressman's supporters
have gathered outside the hospital.
Okay. Good. Let's go.
Ma'am, where's Mr. Raul?
We need your complete family to be there.
It's for the press release photo.
He can't make it.
He's working on a business transaction.
Let's go.
[slow instrumental playing]
[young Ivy] Hey, don't jump!
-Hey! Grab my hand! Hurry!
-[shouting]
You're hurt.
[young Diego] Thank you.
Lily, thanks for helping me out.
Stay away from us!
We don't need your help.
Mr. Torillo, I'm here
because I want to help.
You want to help? Then leave Ardiente!
Who are you, Ms. Aguas?
What do you want from my family?
What do you want from this town?
Ever since you arrived,
bad things started happening.
[thinking] You've changed.
But I've changed too.
There's no point telling you
that I'm Lily.
[slow instrumental playing]
You shouldn't get dragged
into this, Diego.
But if you get in my way…
I have no choice
but to deal with you too.
[woman crying] Congressman.
Congressman.
[sobbing]
Congressman. Poor congressman.
Congressman, get well soon.
[woman] We'll pray for you, Congressman!
-We love you, Congressman!
-Get well soon, Congressman!
We love you, Congressman!
Long live, Congressman Ardiente!
[townsfolk] Long live!
-Viva Ardiente!
-[townsfolk] Viva Ardiente!
-[man] Viva Ardiente!
Hold on.
[man] Long live, Congressman Ardiente!
[townsfolk] Long live!
-[man] Viva Ardiente!
-[townsfolk] Viva Ardiente!
-Ivy.
-Emilia.
I'm glad you're here.
The people really love the congressman.
They really do, Ivy.
They'll support the Ardientes forever.
Hey, come. Join us for a picture.
-No, no. It's okay. I'm fine.
-No, Ivy.
Since you're one
of our supporters, you should join us!
Arnaldo, Diego, it's time for the picture.
Let's stand here by the ambulance.
Diego, Arnaldo, picture!
[tense music playing]
Include the ambulance, please.
-Mom, I'll head to Manila.
-Stay safe there.
Take good care of your grandfather.
Okay, I'll be back
as soon grandpa's settled.
Okay. Keep me posted.
-Ivy.
-Take care, Mr. Mayor.
You don't have to come with me.
But I want you to do something.
-[Jepoy] What is it, Mayor?
-Look after Ms. Aguas.
Protect her at all times.
If I may ask, Mayor,
do you like Ms. Aguas?
You already know the answer, Madrigal.
And you know
that I always get what I want.
I'll go now.
Let's go.
[soft crying]
[townsfolk chanting] Ardiente!
Ardiente! Ardiente!
Ardiente! Ardiente! Ardiente!
Ardiente! Ardiente! Ardiente! Ardiente!
Auntie.
-What's with all the bags?
-Uh…
Wait. What happened?
Did you finally leave them?
No, I didn't.
Does your wife know you're here?
-She might do something to us!
-Auntie, relax.
Emilia thinks I'm with my relatives.
But she doesn't know I'm here.
Why? What happened?
It's a long story.
As much as possible,
I don't want to talk about it.
I don't want to think about it.
And it's better that
you don't know the reason.
How are you? How is she?
Her condition didn't improve.
She's still the same.
Maybe it's better she stays that way.
It's better that
she can't remember anything.
-Come inside, get some rest.
-Okay.
[quiet music playing]
[Belen] Just leave your things here.
She's in there.
Thanks.
[Raul] Love…
I'm back.
[tense music playing]
Love, do you want to catch
some fresh air outside?
Come on.
[bleak instrumental playing]
Now that… [clears throat]
your grandfather's recovering…
uh…
will they still push through
with their project?
I think it'll take some time
before they do.
Grandpa's office is the one leading it.
[somber music playing]
It's not right to celebrate your
grandfather's condition,
but…
it's good news for everyone
that the project was halted.
Ivy, thank you so much
for your time. Sorry, short notice.
Oh, come on, anytime.
What's this for anyway?
You'll know soon enough. Hi, everyone!
Arnaldo, why are you here?
Didn't I tell you I'd be back right away?
-Hi, Ivy.
-Mr. Mayor.
-Okay.
-What's this meeting about?
Let's start the meeting.
Everyone, this is Ms. Ivy Aguas.
I'm sure you already
know Ivy, so let's cut to the chase.
Everyone, this is Ms. Ivy Aguas,
our investor for the EPZ Project.
[applause]
And tomorrow,
she'll be coming with us
for the groundbreaking ceremony.
Groundbreaking?
Yes. Ivy's going ahead
with her investment.
I hadn't mentioned it.
In fact, I'm having our press
releases prepared by tomorrow.
[tense music playing]
Excuse us. Emilia.
What about our problem with the farmers?
Ivy, there is nothing to fix.
For progress to take effect,
someone should make sacrifices.
You know about that, right?
I'm sorry, but those farmers
need to evacuate that land
as soon as possible.
You know, Ivy?
This project will
push through, no matter what,
especially now I'm in charge of it.
And all your plans for this project
will finally come true.
[tense music playing]
Is there something wrong?
You look bothered, Ivy.
[tense music continues]
The Ardientes truly can't
accept no for an answer,
can they, Emilia?
But as I said,
I will not push through with my investment
if it will inconvenience the farmers.
Ivy, tell me.
Why is this so personal to you?
Is there something you want to reveal?
Like skeletons in the closet?
Dark past? Dirty laundry?
Or maybe…
you have relatives who are farmers?
You know, Ivy, as a good businesswoman,
you should learn how
to set aside cheap sentiments
over million-dollar projects.
Excuse me.
[Emilia] Okay.
Let's resume the meeting.
Give me the folder, please.
Arnaldo, would you like to join us?
I thought now that Julio is
out of the game,
it'd be easier for me
to tear down the Ardientes.
Julio is sly.
But Emilia's desperate for power.
[dramatic music playing]
You can end Emilia Ardiente
any time you want.
So we can go back to our normal lives.
Our simple lives.
I wish.
If only it were that easy, Jepoy.
I wish it were easy to heal the
pain that's dragging me down.
But as time goes by,
it hurts even more, it feels heavier.
Like I want to explode.
But this kind of anger…
it can only be tamed
once justice is served.
Only justice can take it away.
So, it's not that simple.
[tense music playing]
I have to be more careful with my plans.
Now that Emilia got what she wanted…
to be the queen of this town…
I will be the hindrance to her ambition.
I'll make sure you won't last
long on your throne,
Emilia Ardiente-Torillo.
Raul, looks like you
really prepared for this.
[Raul chuckles]
Anyway, I still have lots to do inside.
All right. Sure you don't want any?
-I'm good.
-[Raul chuckles]
-I'll leave some for you then.
-Mm-hmm.
Let's give this a try.
Love.
I'm sorry it took me so long
to spend time with you like this.
You know how it is.
I've gotten really busy back home.
[quiet music playing]
But you know what?
If I were to choose…
I'd rather stay here with you.
I won't go back to the Ardientes.
[somber music playing]
[Emilia] Take that to another room.
What's happening, Ma?
[tense music playing]
From now on, I will be
occupying your grandpa's office,
his conference room, everything.
From leading this town, to the Senate.
You're running for the Senate?
But I'm the one
grandpa's been grooming
to someday take his place.
Arnaldo, someday your time will come.
But now, it is my time.
EMILIA ARDIENTE, GAMBLING LORD?
Well, no offense,
you're not the perfect candidate.
Your name's already been
tarnished by that scandal.
All because of the mess Dad left.
Politics is dirty, but for many years
the Ardiente name has stayed clean.
You know why?
Because I'm an expert in
cleaning the dirt from our name.
And while I'm in charge,
no one can ever go against us,
no one can ever go against me.
[ominous music playing]
You should rest. I'll watch over you.
Someday, you'll understand
why I'm doing this.
Someday, you'll forgive me for this…
Jasmin.
Emilia's something else.
I bet she'd even have
Satan himself killed.
[thunder rumbling]
[tense music playing]
Camia?
[grunts]
Camia, hang on.
[tense music playing]
THANK YOU GOVERNOR ARDIENTE
WE LOVE YOU!
THANK YOU!
MAYOR EMILIA ARDIENTE
Raul? Raul?
Auntie. Auntie, I'll carry her.
-What happened?
-Let's go. Just help me get her inside.
Come on. Let's take her inside. Hurry.
All right. It's okay, Auntie.
Who is she?
Her name's Jasmin.
Jasmin?
[quiet music playing]
They may have killed Camia…
but I brought you back as Jasmin.
We'll use that against
the Ardientes someday.
But all this time,
you've been my reason to live.
You bring back my soul
that's slowly been dying
in the hands of the Ardientes.
[phone ringing]
-Hello?
-Hello, Raul?
Play time is over.
Come back here.
Really, Emilia?
After kicking me out
for what I did to your father,
you want me to go back?
Do you think I'm stupid?
Will you send your men after me
if I don't return?
And what's this for?
[sighs]
Oh, I know. You want me to act fake
for the press again.
Emilia, I want you to know that I'm sick
of everything you're doing.
Raul.
Did some bad air pollute your brain?
Wherever you might be right now,
it's turning you crazy again.
You know, now that Papa's not around,
I'm in charge. Me.
I can find you wherever you're hiding
with your dirty tramp.
Now, if you don't want to be
added to my list of trophies
with your filthy hooker,
you'll be home here tomorrow.
[sighs]
[exhales]
Auntie, please take care of Jasmin.
I have to go home.
Look at how the Ardientes
destroyed your life,
like what they did to my brother
when he was alive.
When will you leave that life behind?
Auntie, I'll be free from the
Ardientes soon, but not right now.
How do you think your wife
will take it if she finds out
you're keeping a woman here?
We don't even know her!
Auntie.
It's not that I'm complaining,
but when you brought her here,
you said we'd just help her recover.
Then we'd take her back to her family.
Auntie, she doesn't have a family anymore.
We can't just leave Ca--
We can't just leave Jasmin.
You need to tell the truth.
If Emilia finds out
you're keeping a woman here,
she won't just have your head,
she'll have Jasmin's too.
[tense music playing]
[Emilia] Can you look for my husband?
A queen can't show up
without her king now, can she?
[Ivy] You're so happy right now, Emilia.
Enjoy it while it lasts.
I see that you're still siding
with the Ardientes, Senator.
What's your game, Ms. Aguas?
If I tell you,
you might not want
to play anymore, Senator.
[Belen] It's Jasmin. She's gone.
I've searched the whole house for her.
Auntie, didn't I say to keep
an eye on her at all times?
[Ivy] Hi, Mr. Torillo. You look tense.
[theme music playing]